

#### **OBJECTIVE**

Seeking regional level position to manage credit & risk in reputed Banks and NBFC

To add value towards achievements of organizational goals & simultaneously grow with the process to become the best in this field using my attitude, experience, knowledge & skills.

#### **ADDRESS**

F-204, Saransh Arth, Opp. Silver Flora, Near Vasna Party Plot, G. B. Shah College Road, Vasna, Ahmedabad.

Pin code: 380007

#### CONTACT

#### PHONE:

+91-9909916913

#### **EMAIL:**

chiragshah190@gmail.com

#### LINKEDIN:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/chiragshah-63017265/

# CHIRAG SHAH

SR. AREA CREDIT MANAGER

#### **CAREER SNAPSHOT**

A dynamic person offering 16+ years of experience in managing Credit & Risk in various types of products of the Banks and NBFC. Presently, associated with Cholamandalam Investment and finance Company Limited as Senior Area Credit Manager - SME based out at Ahmedabad for handling entire Gujarat Region.

#### **SKILLS**

- 1. Credit Analysis
- 2. Innovative Policy
- 3. Sector wise analysis
- 4. Team Management
- 5. ERM and Risk Assessment
- 6. Compliance Management
- 7. Management Consulting
- 8. Financial planning & analysis

#### **CURRENT WORK EXPERIENCE**

## [CHOLAMANDALAM INVESTMENT & FINANCE CO. LTD] [SR. AREA CREDIT MANAGER] [SINCE MAY-2021 ONWARDS]

- Managing underwriting of cases for Gujarat region & other states of India for working capital loans, supply chain management, machinery and project loans and secured and unsecured business loans for SMEs & MSMEs
- Having sanctioning authority up to Rs. 100 lacs.
- Analyzing the credit proposals from all the aspects considering financial, non-financial and various other factors impacting the market.
- Liaise with clients, externals and internal team and subject experts for risk and credit worthiness of the borrower.
- Experience in digitization / automation of credit process.
- Experience in designing credit score cards for underwriting using alternate data points which is the new gen tech model.
- Responsible for managing a team of branch credit managers and credit analyst.

#### **PERSONAL DETAILS**

- DOB: 15<sup>™</sup> AUGUST 1984
- Marital Status: Married
- Nationality: Indian

#### **FAMILY DETAILS**

Father's Name: Mr. Bipinbhai Shah Mother's Name: Mrs. Dinaben Shah Spouse Name: Mrs. Foram Shah

#### **COMPUTER SKILLS**

- MS Office Excellent
- Adobe Suite Good
- Tally ERP Good

#### **LANGUAGES**

- Gujarati Native language
- Hindi Excellent
- English Excellent

#### **HOBBIES**

- 1. Reading,
- 2. Travelling,
- 3. Music,
- 4. Playing outdoor games

#### **REFERENCE**

- Mr. Akash Sethi Director & NCM Northern Arc Capital Contact: +91-9594943368
- 2. Mr. Pradeep Bothra RCM West Hero Fincorp Limited Contact: +91-8265062733

#### **PAST WORK EXPERIENCE**

## [HERO FINCORP LIMITED] [AREA CREDIT MANAGER] [12/2014 TO 05/2021]

- Authority to sanction cases up to Rs. 75 lacs for the SME Cases under the corporate finance in Hero Fincorp Limited.
- Responsible for credit and risk for SME under Corporate Finance vertical of the organization for Gujarat Region.
- Take care of SME working capital loans, bills discounting for supply chain management, business loan, machinery loan, project loan, corporate term loan against property etc.
- Team Handling of Credit Analyst based out at Ahmedabad.
- Handling credit processing and underwriting for SME customers along with eligibility calculations, PD management, and Credit appraisal note preparation & decisioning.
- Responsible to ensure and adherence to credit policy and defined processes, TAT management and fraud risk management.

## [INDUSIND BANK LIMITED] [DEPUTY MANAGER - BBG] [09/2014 TO 12/2014]

- Responsible for overall credit & risk administration of (North Gujarat)
- Handling products related to working capital which includes fund based and non-fund-based facilities, corporate term loans and term loan against properties.
- Verification and analysis of the financials, banking, loan accounts, personal discussion with customer and handling timely sanctions of the required fund based / non-fund-based facilities.
- Monitoring the existing portfolio which helps in data maintenance and for getting early warning signals.

## [DCB BANK LIMITED EARSTWHILE DEVELOPMENT CREDIT BANK] [ASSISTANT MANAGER] [06/2011 TO 09/2014]

- Responsible for overall credit & risk administration of Ahmedabad.
- Verification and analysis of the financials, banking, loan accounts, personal discussion with customer and handling timely sanctioning of the required fund based / non-fund-based facilities, corporate term loans and term loan against properties.
- Mapping and analyzing the trend of customer's accounts and providing timely & correct feedback to the organization.
- Preparing the various types of MIS which helps in data maintenance and for getting early warning signals.

### [KOTAK MAHINDRA BANK LTD – ON ROLLS OF T&M]

[CREDIT & RELATIONSHIP EXECUTIVE] [12/2010 TO 06/2011]

[ICICI BANK LTD - ON ROLLS OF I-PROCESS SERVICES PVT LTD]
[CREDIT EXECUTIVE] [10/2005 TO 12/2010]

#### **EDUCATION**

#### [PGDIFA - PG DIPLOMA IN INVESTMENT AND FINANCIAL ANALYSIS]

[S. D. SCHOOL OF COMMERCE, GUJARAT UNIVERSITY] [2004-2005, Obtained first class, 61%]

#### [B.COM - BACHELOR OF COMMERCE]

[SOM-LALIT COLLEGE OF COMMERCE, GUJARAT UNIVERSITY] [2001-2004, Obtained first class, 66]